If you want to get on in life, there’s things you
have to ignore so you can keep on.
Small Things Like These is a drama film directed by Tim Mielants.
In 1985, while working as a coal merchant to support his family, Bill Furlong discovers disturbing secrets kept by the local convent and uncovers
truths of his own; forcing him to confront his past and the complicit silence of a small Irish town controlled by the Catholic Church.
Bill Furlong, played by Cillian Murphy.
Sister Mary, played by Emily Watson.
Mrs. Wilson, played by Michelle Fairley.
Eileen Furlong, played by Eileen Walsh.
Sarah Redmond, played by Zara Devlin.
Sister Carmel, played by Clare Dunne.
Small Things like These is a 2024 historical drama film directed by Tim Mielants
and adapted by Enda Walsh from the 2021 novel by Claire Keegan.
It stars Cillian Murphy (who also serves as a producer), Eileen Walsh,
Michelle Fairley, Emily Watson, Clare Dunne, and Helen Behan.
An international co-production between Ireland and Belgium, its plot
focuses on the infamous Magdalene laundries in Ireland.
Small Things like These had its world premiere at the 74th Berlin International Film Festival on 15
February 2024, and was released in Ireland and the United Kingdom on 1 November 2024.
It received positive reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of small town, husband wife
relationship, based on novel or book, choir, flashback.
The tone is dark and emotional.